Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about buying clothes.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊聊买衣服的事。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to go and get some clothes but on this occasion, we're going to get a suit
我们要去买些衣服，但这次，我们要买一套西装，
and we're going to have it made especially for us.
而且是专门为我们定做的。
So before we get started, why don't we take a look at one keyword that we have in Vocabulary
所以在开始之前，我们先来看看词汇预览中的一个关键词。
Preview.
预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, this word makes me think of things that are very rich and soft.
好的，这个词让我想到非常奢华柔软的东西。
It's a fabric, right?
它是一种面料，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
It's a kind of textile.
它是一种纺织品。
It's called cashmere.
它叫羊绒。
Cashmere.
羊绒。
So maybe you've heard of cashmere wool.
你可能听说过羊绒羊毛。
It's a special kind of wool that comes from animals.
它是一种来自动物的特殊羊毛。
So this is a textile or a fabric that is commonly used to make pants, nice pants or suits for
所以这是一种常用于制作裤子、高档裤子或男士西装的纺织品或面料。
men.
男士西装。
Or scars or sweaters.
或者围巾、毛衣。
If you've ever had a cashmere sweater, you know it's very luxurious, very soft.
如果你有过羊绒毛衣，就知道它非常奢华、非常柔软。
So it can be a little bit expensive depending on the quality and that's what we're going
所以根据质量不同，它可能有点贵，这就是我们现在要看的。
to be looking at now.
我们现在要看的。
We're going to be making a suit out of cashmere.
我们要用羊绒做一套西装。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time.
那么，我们先来听一遍对话。
Welcome to Bill's Fabric World.
欢迎来到比尔面料世界。
What can I do for you today?
今天我能为您做些什么？
I was wondering if you guys also tailor clothes.
我想问一下你们这里也做衣服裁剪吗？
Sure we do.
当然做。
We're the best tailors in the country.
我们是全国最好的裁缝。
What is it that you need exactly?
您具体需要什么？
Well I'm looking to get a custom made suit.
嗯，我想定做一套西装。
Excellent.
太好了。
We have the finest cashmeres at affordable prices.
我们有最优质的羊绒，价格实惠。
How about we get you measured?
我们先给您量一下尺寸吧？
Let's start off by measuring the width of your shoulders.
先从量您的肩宽开始。
Now let's measure the length of your arms and this bit around your neck here.
现在量一下您的臂长和脖子这里。
Can you make sure you leave a little extra space in the collar?
您能确保在领口留点多余空间吗？
My neck gets easily irritated.
我的脖子容易不舒服。
No problem.
没问题。
Now for your pants, let me just measure your waist and the inseam.
现在量您的裤子，让我量一下您的腰围和内缝长。
You might also want to leave a little extra room in the waist area.
您可能也想在腰部留点多余空间。
I tend to gain a few pounds over the holidays.
我假期容易长几斤肉。
Okay.
好的。
Now you can pick your fabric and pattern design.
现在您可以挑选面料和图案设计了。
Please follow me.
请跟我来。
So this reminds me of something that people used to do a lot more often.
这让我想起以前人们更常做的事。
So you'd go to the tailor and you'd have some clothes made.
就是去裁缝那里定做衣服。
Most people don't do this anymore.
现在大多数人都不这么做了。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's actually really interesting.
其实挺有意思的。
Maybe because it's more expensive nowadays or tailors are harder to find.
可能是因为现在更贵了，或者裁缝更难找了。
That's right.
没错。
So let's learn about the words first and what they mean and then maybe we can talk about
所以先学学这些词的意思，然后也许我们可以在节目最后聊聊这个。
this at the end of today's show.
节目最后。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright, so today on language takeaway we have a word that is a noun and a verb.
好的，今天在语言要点里，我们有一个既是名词又是动词的词。
So as you mentioned, the person that makes suits is a tailor.
就像你提到的，做西装的人是裁缝。
That's right.
没错。
You can say, my uncle is a tailor.
你可以说，我叔叔是个裁缝。
He makes clothes for famous people.
他为名人做衣服。
But this word is also a verb.
但这个词也是动词。
That means it's an action word.
意思是它是一个动作词。
We can say, my uncle the tailor, he tailors clothes.
我们可以说，我叔叔那个裁缝，他裁剪衣服。
Okay, so to tailor clothes.
好的，所以是裁剪衣服。
And what does it mean when you say to tailor?
那你说“裁剪”是什么意思呢？
Well, it can have two meanings.
嗯，它有两个意思。
The first is what we learn about in today's dialogue.
第一个是我们在今天对话中学到的。
It means to make clothes.
意思是做衣服。
So to make a shirt or to make a pair of pants.
比如做衬衫或做裤子。
But these days we often say to tailor which means to fix something.
但现在我们常说“裁剪”，意思是修改东西。
So for example, Marco, if you buy a pair of pants and they're too long, you can have them
比如，Marco，如果你买了一条裤子太长，你可以拿去改。
tailored.
拿去改。
Have them tailored.
And that means that I am going to have them fixed so they fit me properly.
这意味着我要把它们修改得合身。
Exactly.
没错。
This is a lot more common right now.
现在这更常见了。
Okay, so we're going to be tailoring clothes.
好的，所以我们要裁剪衣服。
Now if any of you have ever been to the tailor, what they do is they measure you.
如果你们谁去过裁缝店，他们会给你量尺寸。
And what do they measure?
他们量什么呢？
Well, in this case, they get the width of your shoulders.
嗯，在这种情况下，他们量的是你肩膀的宽度。
What's really great about these upcoming words is that they're useful in math as well.
这些即将学到的词很棒，因为它们在数学里也很有用。
Math and basic measurements.
数学和基本测量。
So width is how big something is across.
所以宽度是指某物横向有多大。
How wide something is.
某物有多宽。
Exactly.
没错。
Wide, width.
宽，宽度。
Okay, so that's the width.
好的，那就是宽度。
Now your shoulders, they are wide.
现在你的肩膀，它们很宽。
And well, your legs on the other hand, your legs and arms, you don't measure the width
而另一方面，你的腿，你的腿和胳膊，通常不量宽度，
usually, you measure the length.
而是量长度。
How long they are.
它们有多长。
Okay, so width and length.
好的，所以是宽度和长度。
Now just to throw it in there, this wasn't in the dialogue, but what would be the other
现在顺便提一下，对话里没提到，但另一个
measure word?
测量词是什么？
So the third word would be height.
第三个词是高度。
So you think of a rectangle, you have the width, how wide something is, the length,
所以想象一个长方形，你有宽度，即某物有多宽；长度，
how long it is, and the height, how tall it is.
即它有多长；以及高度，即它有多高。
How tall it is, right.
它有多高，对。
So width, length, and height.
所以是宽度、长度和高度。
All right.
好的。
Now that we've measured our arms and legs, now we want to measure our waist.
现在我们量完了胳膊和腿，接下来要量腰围。
Okay, this is the important one.
好的，这是重要的一项。
This is also the sensitive one.
这也是敏感的一项。
If you find that you've gained some weight, we measure the waist.
如果你发现自己胖了，我们就量腰围。
Okay, that's how big you are around your stomach.
好的，那是你肚子周围有多大。
And so usually we measure this in a circle.
通常我们绕着圈量。
Okay, so you've heard of a 26 inch waist or a 32 inch waist.
好的，所以你听说过26英寸腰围或32英寸腰围。
This is the size of your stomach.
这是你肚子的大小。
Okay, so it's just above your hips, right?
好的，就在臀部上方，对吧？
As you say, it's your stomach.
就像你说的，是你的肚子。
And well, we've measured the waist.
嗯，我们量了腰围。
And now in men especially, they measure the inseam.
现在尤其是男士，他们会量内缝长。
Now this is very particular for tailors and having suits made.
这对裁缝和定制西装来说非常特别。
What is the inseam of your pants?
你裤子的内缝长是多少？
Well think of the word in, inside.
想想“内”这个词，内部。
This is the inside of your pants.
这是你裤子的内侧。
So from your foot to the middle of your pants where your zipper starts.
所以从你的脚到裤子中间拉链开始的地方。
So that's not the outside length, it's the inside length.
所以那不是外侧长度，而是内侧长度。
Now for example, skirts, they don't have inseams, right?
比如，裙子就没有内缝长，对吧？
No, because there's no inside, there's no middle.
没有，因为没有内侧，没有中间。
So it's just like a circle.
所以它就像一个圆圈。
But in pants or shorts, you have an inseam.
但在裤子或短裤里，你有内缝长。
That's where it's connected in the middle.
那是它们在中间连接的地方。
All right, so also in shorts, very interesting.
好的，短裤也一样，很有趣。
So you can measure the inseam of pants or shorts.
所以你可以量裤子或短裤的内缝长。
All right, so very interesting and particular words for tailors.
好的，这些词对裁缝来说非常有趣和特别。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back shortly.
我们再来听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Welcome to Bill's Fabric World.
欢迎来到比尔布料世界。
What can I do for you today?
今天我能为您做些什么？
I was wondering if you guys also tailor clothes.
我想知道你们是否也做衣服修改。
Sure we do.
当然可以。
We have the best tailors in the country.
我们有全国最好的裁缝。
What is it that you need exactly?
您具体需要什么？
Well, I'm looking to get a custom made suit.
嗯，我想定制一套西装。
Excellent.
太好了。
We have the finest cashmeres at affordable prices.
我们有最优质的羊绒，价格实惠。
How about we get you measured?
我们先给您量尺寸吧？
Let's start off by measuring the width of your shoulders.
我们先量一下您肩膀的宽度。
Now let's measure the length of your arms and this bit around your neck here.
现在量一下您胳膊的长度和脖子这里这一圈。
Can you make sure you leave a little extra space in the collar?
您能在领口留点额外空间吗？
My neck gets easily irritated.
我的脖子容易不舒服。
No problem.
没问题。
Now for your pants, let me just measure your waist and the inseam.
现在量您的裤子，让我量一下您的腰围和内缝长。
You might also want to leave a little extra room in the waist area.
您可能也想在腰部留点额外空间。
I tend to gain a few pounds over the holidays.
我假期容易胖几磅。
Okay.
好的。
Now you can pick your fabric and pattern design.
现在您可以挑选面料和图案设计了。
Please follow me.
请跟我来。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have three key phrases that we found in this dialogue.
所以我们在对话中找到了三个关键短语。
So let's take a look at them now in Fluency Builder.
现在让我们在流利度构建器中看看它们。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
This first phrase is the topic of today's lesson.
第一个短语是今天课程的主题。
We talked a little bit about measurements for a suit, but in particular we're getting
我们聊了一点西装的测量，但特别提到了
a custom made suit.
定制西装。
Okay.
好的。
So this word custom made.
所以这个词“定制”。
Well, custom is important, it means special or unique.
嗯，“定制”很重要，意思是特别或独特。
There's no other like it.
没有其他一样的。
So we could talk about custom cars.
所以我们可以聊聊定制车。
That means a car that has been fixed especially for you.
那是指一辆专门为你改装的车。
Okay.
好的。
So a custom made suit would be a suit that was made specifically for your height, for
所以一套定制西装就是根据你的身高、
how big your waist is, etc.
腰围等量身定做的西装。
Specifically for you.
专门为你做的。
Right.
对。
So a suit that I buy at the department store is just a normal suit.
所以我在百货商店买的西装只是普通西装。
But a suit that I have made for me is a custom made suit.
但为我量身定做的西装就是定制西装。
Okay.
好的。
So as you said, you can use it for cars, a custom made car, or maybe for example, a custom
所以就像你说的，可以用在车上，比如定制车，或者举个例子，定制
made.
的。
Custom made kitchen.
定制厨房。
That means that you get to pick every single part of the kitchen that you want.
那意味着你可以挑选厨房的每一个部分。
Many people do that, right?
很多人这么做，对吧？
They have custom built or custom made homes.
他们会有定制建造或定制的房子。
Yeah, that's always something I've wanted to do, but I hear that it's much more expensive
是啊，那一直是我想要做的事，但我听说那比买普通房子贵得多。
than getting a normal homemade.
比买普通房子贵得多。
All right.
好的。
So that's the first key phrase.
所以这是第一个关键短语。
Now moving on, when we talk about measuring, we say, I measured.
现在继续，当我们谈论测量时，我们说，我测量了。
I measured the length of this street.
我测量了这条街的长度。
Right.
对。
Or let's measure you so we can see how big you are.
或者让我们量一下你，看看你有多大。
But if you notice in the dialogue, we use the passive voice.
但如果你注意到对话中，我们用了被动语态。
He says, let's get you measured.
他说，让我们给你量一下。
Okay.
好的。
I got measured or it got measured.
我被量了或者它被量了。
To get measured, as you say, is the passive voice.
被量，就像你说的，是被动语态。
Now what's the difference between passive and active?
那么被动和主动有什么区别呢？
All right.
好的。
So basically what happens here is we are concentrating on the person and the action falling upon
所以基本上这里的情况是，我们关注的是人以及作用在你身上的动作，
you, for example.
比如。
So I got measured.
所以我被量了。
What happened to me?
我发生了什么？
I got measured.
我被量了。
Who did it?
谁做的？
Who measured you?
谁量的你？
We don't know.
我们不知道。
We don't care.
我们不在乎。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
The point, the important part is that you were measured.
重点是，重要的是你被量了。
You got measured, but we could have a different phrase.
你被量了，但我们可能有不同的说法。
We say, for example, I will measure this table or he measures the height of the door and
比如，我们会说，我会量这张桌子，或者他量了门的高度，
we know he measures.
我们知道他量了。
I will measure.
我会量。
We know who the actor is.
我们知道动作的执行者是谁。
That means it's active voice because the focus is on who's doing this action.
那意味着是主动语态，因为重点是谁在做这个动作。
And in passive voice, the important thing is who is receiving the action.
而在被动语态中，重要的是谁在接受这个动作。
Right.
对。
Now it's a little bit complicated because as you can see, measured is in the past, but
现在这有点复杂，因为如你所见，measured 是过去式，但
we're not really talking about the past.
我们并不是真的在谈论过去。
So it may get a little bit complicated.
所以可能会有点复杂。
We can take a more in-depth look at that in the community section.
我们可以在社区部分更深入地探讨。
You can ask a couple of questions.
你可以问一些问题。
We'll place a couple of examples, but it's kind of hard to get into the grammar over
我们会放一些例子，但通过音频播客深入讲解语法有点难，
an audio podcast, right?
对吧？
That's true.
没错。
So that's why we have the practice space on the website.
所以这就是为什么我们在网站上设有练习区。
All right.
好的。
So moving on, we have our last phrase.
那么继续，我们有最后一个短语。
And when he was talking about the waist and how he should leave a little bit of extra
当他谈到腰围以及应该留一点额外空间时，
room, it's because he tends to gain a few pounds.
是因为他容易长几磅肉。
Okay.
好的。
So to gain a few pounds is like gaining a kilo.
所以长几磅肉就像长一公斤。
It means to gain weight over the holidays.
意思是假期期间体重增加。
And in this case, to tend to, I tend to means I normally or I usually.
在这种情况下，tend to，我 tend to 意思是我通常或我一般。
So for example, Marco, what do you tend to eat for breakfast?
比如，Marco，你早餐通常吃什么？
I tend to eat scrambled eggs and a glass of yogurt.
我通常吃炒鸡蛋和一杯酸奶。
That's healthy.
那很健康。
Do you tend to run late in the morning?
你早上容易迟到吗？
Yes.
是的。
True.
确实。
Right.
对。
So tend to, it's a tendency, is what usually happens.
所以 tend to，是一种倾向，是通常发生的事。
It's normal.
很正常。
All right.
好的。
So very interesting phrases, very interesting words.
非常有趣的短语，非常有趣的词汇。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time?
我们最后再听一遍对话怎么样？
Welcome to Bill's Fabric World.
欢迎来到比尔布料世界。
What can I do for you today?
今天我能为您做些什么？
I was wondering if you guys also tailor clothes.
我想知道你们是否也做衣服裁剪。
Sure we do.
当然，我们做。
We have the best tailors in the country.
我们有全国最好的裁缝。
What is it that you need exactly?
您具体需要什么？
Well, I'm looking to get a custom made suit.
嗯，我想定制一套西装。
Excellent.
太好了。
We have the finest cashmeres at affordable prices.
我们有最优质的开司米羊绒，价格实惠。
How about we get you measured?
我们先给您量一下尺寸怎么样？
Let's start off by measuring the width of your shoulders.
我们先从测量您的肩宽开始。
Now let's measure the length of your arms and this bit around your neck here.
现在量一下您的臂长和脖子这里这一圈。
Can you make sure you leave a little extra space in the collar?
您能确保在领口留一点额外空间吗？
My neck gets easily irritated.
我的脖子容易过敏。
No problem.
没问题。
Now for your pants, let me just measure your waist and the inseam.
现在量您的裤子，让我量一下您的腰围和内缝长。
You might also want to leave a little extra room in the waist area.
您可能还想在腰部留一点额外空间。
I tend to gain a few pounds over the holidays.
我假期容易长几磅肉。
Okay.
好的。
Now you can pick your fabric and pattern design.
现在您可以挑选面料和图案设计了。
Please follow me.
请跟我来。
All right.
好的。
So we talked earlier about how most people buy their clothes at a department store or
我们之前谈到大多数人是在百货商店或
a clothing store.
服装店买衣服。
Have you seen much of this?
你见过很多这种情况吗？
You know, maybe back in Ecuador it's more common than in America.
你知道，也许在厄瓜多尔比在美国更常见。
Yeah.
是的。
Usually people just go to a department store and get suits for example, but it's actually
通常人们只是去百货商店买西装之类的，但实际上
very common as well because it's kind of in their artisans to be like a shoemaker or to
这也很常见，因为他们的手工艺传统中，比如做鞋匠或
be a tailor.
做裁缝是很自然的。
So actually people like it more and go to tailors because they kind of become renowned
所以实际上人们更喜欢去裁缝那里，因为他们会变得有名气，
like, oh, he used to make suits for the president.
比如，“哦，他以前给总统做过西装。”
So you know, people really, really like to get suits made there and obviously they fit
所以你知道，人们真的非常喜欢在那里定制西装，显然它们
much better.
合身得多。
You feel more comfortable.
你感觉更舒服。
And you look better.
而且你看起来更好看。
Yeah.
是的。
As I've said before, you know, I see people who buy all these suits.
就像我之前说的，你知道，我看到有人买所有这些西装。
My brother, for example, they never quite fit right.
比如我哥哥，它们从来都不太合身。
You can tell it's a little too big in the shoulders.
你能看出肩膀那里有点太大。
My brother's tall, so his pants are always a little bit too short.
我哥哥个子高，所以他的裤子总是有点短。
But when you come to a place like China and most people can get these suits made for them,
但当你来到像中国这样的地方，大多数人可以定制这些西装，
they just look fabulous.
他们看起来棒极了。
It looks very, very nice.
看起来非常非常好看。
Yeah.
是的。
So maybe you guys can tell us if you've ever had anything tailor made, not only guys' suits,
所以也许你们可以告诉我们，你们有没有定制过任何东西，不仅是男士西装，
but girls also get tailor made dresses, tailor made blouses.
女士也会定制连衣裙、定制衬衫。
I always get coats made actually because my shoulders are broad and so it's hard for me
我其实总是定制外套，因为我的肩膀宽，所以很难
to find coats that fit right.
找到合身的外套。
But if I get one custom made, it looks really good.
但如果我定制一件，看起来就很好。
Right.
对。
So come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Leave your questions and comments there and we'll see you guys later.
在那里留下你们的问题和评论，我们下次再见。
Until next time, guys.
下次见，各位。
Bye.
再见。
Man that hit.
哇，那一下真带劲。